<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE resume PUBLIC "-//Sean Kelly//DTD Resume 1.5.1//EN"
  "http://www.altova.com/schemas/xmlresume/resume.dtd">
<?altova_sps http://www.altova.com/sps/template/xmlresume/xmlresume.sps?>
<resume xmlns="http://xmlresume.sourceforge.net/resume/0.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<header>
		<name id="sgirl">
			<firstname>XML</firstname>
			<surname>Spy</surname>
		</name>
		<address>
			<zip>01915-6181</zip>
			<state>Massachusetts</state>
			<city>Beverly</city>
			<street>900 Cummings Center Suite 314-T</street>
		</address>
		<contact>
			<phone location="work">978-816-1600</phone>
			<fax>978-816-1606</fax>
			<email>spygirl@altova.com</email>
		</contact>
	</header>
	<referees>
		<referee>
			<name>
				<firstname/>
				<surname/>
			</name>
		</referee>
	</referees>
	<academics>
		<degrees>
			<degree>
				<level/>
				<gpa>
					<score/>
				</gpa>
			</degree>
		</degrees>
	</academics>
	<objective targets="xmltechnology">
		<para>To achieve successful integration of XML on the web, corporate infrastructure, and transactional systems. Apply skills acquired though previous versions to the newest version to result in best XML developer in the world.</para>
	</objective>
	<skillarea>
		<title>XML Editing and Validation</title>
		<skillset>
			<skill>*  Code completion</skill>
			<skill>* Context-sensitive entry helpers</skill>
			<skill>* Line numbers &amp; source folding</skill>
			<skill>* Built-in XML validation and well-formedness checker</skill>
			<skill>* Find-in-files window for find &amp; replace in files &amp; entire projects </skill>
			<skill>* Editing Office Open XML Microsoft Office 2007 data</skill>
			<skill>* One-click comment in / out</skill>
			<skill>* Pretty-printing of XML files </skill>
			<skill>* Multi-lingual spell checking </skill>
			<skill/>
			<skill>* CSS editor</skill>
			<skill>* Project management features</skill>
			<skill>* Enhanced Grid View shows the hierarchical structure of any XML-compliant document through a set of nested containers</skill>
			<skill/>
			<skill>* Authentic view which allows you to view Authentic forms created in StyleVision® 2008</skill>
			<skill>* Integrated browser view of XMLSpy® 2008 to immediately preview any XML file that is associated with an XSL stylesheet, or  view the output from an XSLT transformation to HTML </skill>
			<skill>* Validation window which provides granular details about each error, including:

The reason for the error
A link to the error in the working XML file
A link to the corresponding definition(s) in the associated schema file
Links to relevant information in the applicable specification on the W3C Web site</skill>
			<skill>* Visual XML differencing utility for visually comparing XML files and directories</skill>
			<skill>* XInclude and XPointer support</skill>
		</skillset>
	</skillarea>
	<skillarea>
		<title>DTD and Schema Editing</title>
		<skillset>
			<skill>* DTD Editor</skill>
			<skill>* Graphical XML Schema Editor</skill>
			<skill>Support for aggregate Schemas</skill>
			<skill>* Generation of DTD/Schema from database</skill>
			<skill> * Editing of embedded Schemas inside WSDL files</skill>
			<skill>* Supports integration with Altova SchemaAgent® 2008, the revolutionary new tool for modeling and managing advanced schemas and other XML-based files in workgroups</skill>
		</skillset>
	</skillarea>
	<skillarea>
		<title>XSLT Debugger</title>
		<skillset>
			<skill>* View and change variables during execution</skill>
			<skill>* Define breakpoints in the XML and XSLT files, and tracepoints in the XSLT document</skill>
			<skill>* Debug XML and XSL files in Grid and Text View</skill>
			<skill>* Node-based Breakpoint Management</skill>
		</skillset>
	</skillarea>
	<skillarea>
		<title>Programming-language support</title>
		<skillset>
			<skill>* Scripting and COM API</skill>
			<skill>* Built-in code generator that automatically generates Java, C++, or Microsoft C# class files </skill>
			<skill>* Export XML Schema files as UML 2 project files for Altova UModel® 2008.</skill>
			<skill>* Support for various XML document and schema repository interfaces, as well as major version control systems</skill>
			<skill>* API for system integration and automation purposes that is available in COM and Java versions </skill>
			<skill>* ASP Support</skill>
			<skill>* Forms Editor and ActiveX Controls Integration</skill>
			<skill>* Support for Visual Studio integration</skill>
			<skill>* Support for integration with the Eclipse Platform</skill>
			<skill>* Built-in editing support for all important Java™ 2 Platform, Enterprise Edition (J2EE) configuration files</skill>
			<skill>* Supports the editing of JSP files through intelligent entry-helpers for both HTML and JSP elements</skill>
		</skillset>
	</skillarea>
	<skillarea>
		<title>Web Services Support</title>
		<skillset>
			<skill>* SOAP Client &amp; Debugger</skill>
			<skill>* WSDL Validation</skill>
			<skill>* Graphical WSDL Editor</skill>
		</skillset>
	</skillarea>
	<skillarea>
		<title>Database and Legacy support</title>
		<skillset>
			<skill>* Tamino XML Database management</skill>
			<skill>* Generation of DTD/Schema from database</skill>
			<skill>* Hierarchical Database Import based on XML Schema</skill>
			<skill>* Database Export/Import</skill>
			<skill>* Powerful Database Query window allows you to perform queries against the database, edit the data, and even commit your changes to the database (commit currently only enabled for IBM DB2)</skill>
			<skill>* XML-enabled databases - specialized support</skill>
		</skillset>
	</skillarea>
	<skillarea>
		<title>Connectivity</title>
		<skillset>
			<skill>* File system accessible through HTTP, WebDAV, or FTP</skill>
			<skill> </skill>
		</skillset>
	</skillarea>
	<skillarea>
		<title>Project Management</title>
		<skillset>
			<skill>* Source-Code Control System Interface (VSS, CVS, and compatibles</skill>
			<skill>* Linking to physical Filesystem folders</skill>
		</skillset>
	</skillarea>
	<skillarea>
		<title>XQuery Editing, Profiling and Debugging</title>
		<skillset>
			<skill>* Native, schema-aware support for XQuery 1.0 using a standards-conformant XQuery engine</skill>
			<skill>* Debugging XQuery, providing breakpoints and variable's values, over XML from files or databases</skill>
			<skill>* XQuery profiler monitors your XQuery code as it runs and record how long each process takes You can then use this information to determine which parts of the code are taking the longest time and optimize any problem areas or bottlenecks
</skill>
		</skillset>
	</skillarea>
	<history>
		<job>
			<jobtitle>Award winning IDE for XML</jobtitle>
			<employer>Altova, Inc</employer>
			<period>
				<from>
					<date>
						<year>2002</year>
					</date>
				</from>
				<to>
					<date>
						<year>2007</year>
					</date>
				</to>
			</period>
			<description>
				<para>The next generation of internet software will encompass web services, mobile devices, smart agents, desktops and servers, collaborating seamlessly across the network. At the heart of this solution are XML based technologies such as SOAP, XML Schema, XSL and WSDL which enable unprecedented application interoperability </para>
			</description>
			<projects>
				<project title="Altova All Inclusive Soulution">Was the ultimate developer tool for all XML-related work</project>
				<project>Made for Easy Deployment of XML content editing throughout the Enterprise</project>
				<project>Utilized the power of XML Spy in your Server Environment</project>
			</projects>
			<achievements>
				<achievement>Was the winner of the Best of Tech Ed 2003, 2004, 2007</achievement>
				<achievement>Visual Studio Magazine Readers Choice Awards 2002, 2003, 2004, 2007</achievement>
			</achievements>
		</job>
	</history>
	<memberships>
		<title>Partnerships</title>
		<membership>
			<organization>World Wide Web Consortium</organization>
			<description>
				<para>Altova is an active member of the W3C and is committed to delivering standards&#x2011;based platform&#x2011;independent development solutions that are powerful, affordable, and easy to use.</para>
			</description>
		</membership>
	</memberships>
	<awards>
		<title>Honors and Awards</title>
		<award>
			<title>Altova XMLSpy was named as a winner of the Best of Tech Ed Awards 2007 in the Developer Tools and Technologies category by Penton Media’s Windows IT Pro, SQL Server Magazine and Office and Sharepoint Pro.com. </title>
		</award>
		<award>
			<title>For the fifth consecutive year, Altova was named to the SD Times 100 list of leaders and innovators in the software development industry. SD Times honored Altova in the Tools and Environments category, citing that &quot;XMLSpy is still awesome, but the vision has expanded to include transformation, query, Web services and application design.&quot; </title>
		</award>
		<award>
			<title>Altova XMLSpy received the 2007 Readers’ Choice Merit Award from Visual Studio Magazine in the Web Design and Development Tools category. The winners are chosen by Visual Studio Magazine’s readers and honor excellent software in 22 development categories. </title>
		</award>
		<award>
			<title>Altova XMLSpy was selected for honorable mention in the Utility category in the 2007 asp.netPRO Readers&apos; Choice Awards. The awards are chosen by readers to honor products and services that make their ASP.NET development more efficient, productive, and profitable.</title>
		</award>
		<award>
			<title>XMLSpy was named the best-selling XML tool for fifth Consecutive year in the XML Tools category. The prestigious 2006 Programmer’s Paradise Riding the Crest® Award recognizes the products that its customers have selected most often and “ride high on the wave” above all others.</title>
		</award>
		<award>
			<title>Altova XMLSpy has earned the SSWUG.org Five Star Rating Award.</title>
		</award>
		<award>
			<title>XMLSpy was named a platinum winner in the XML category of the 2006 SQL Server Magazine Editors’ Choice Awards. Platinum and gold winners were chosen in 17 categories based on the product’s strategic importance to the market, its competitive advantages, and the value to the customer. </title>
		</award>
		<award>
			<title>Altova XMLSpy won the 2005 Programmer&apos;s Paradise Riding the Crest Award in the XML Tool category. This is the fourth consecutive year that XMLSpy has been named the best-selling XML product.</title>
		</award>
	</awards>
	<clearances>
		<clearance>
			<level>Top Secret</level>
			<organization>Altova, Inc.</organization>
			<date targets="">
				<month>January</month>
				<year targets="">1999</year>
			</date>
			<note targets="">
				<para targets="">Special Agent</para>
			</note>
		</clearance>
	</clearances>
	<lastModified>
		<date>
			<month>October</month>
			<year>2007</year>
		</date>
	</lastModified>
</resume>
