<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
               "http://www.altova.com/schemas/docbook/docbookx.dtd">
<?altova_sps http://www.altova.com/sps/template/publishing/docbook.sps?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.altova.com/stylesheets/docbook/xhtml/docbook.xsl"?>
<book>
	<part>
		<title>StyleVision</title>
		<chapter>
			<title>Stylesheet Designer</title>
			<sect1>
				<title>Altova StyleVision® 2010 is a graphical stylesheet designer for transforming XML, XBRL, and database content into HTML, RTF, PDF, Word 2007+ (OOXML), and Authentic® electronic forms.</title>
				<para>Designing stylesheets in StyleVision is a highly flexible, visual drag-and-drop process. You simply select components from your data source(s), drag them onto the design pane, and specify their presentation and layout properties using the user-friendly entry helper windows. Alternatively, you can layout your design in its entirety and then add content later - in the same manner that you would approach common desktop publishing applications.
</para>
				<para>StyleVision stylesheet designs can be based on one or multiple XML, DTD, XBRL, and database source(s). This means your design can integrate data from multiple XML sources, or even combine data from an XML Schema and a relational database. In fact, you can even create designs to publish XML documents stored inside relational database columns (currently supported for IBM DB2 and SQL Server only).</para>
				<para>Each design simultaneously produces standards-conformant XSLT 1.0/2.0 and XSL:FO stylesheets, the corresponding output in HTML, RTF, PDF, Word 2007+, and an Authentic e-Form. This makes StyleVision the ultimate tool for single source, multi-channel publishing of XML, XBRL, and database data.</para>
				<para>
					<inlinegraphic fileref="http://www.altova.com/images/shots/stylesheet_designer.gif"/>
				</para>
			</sect1>
			<sect1>
				<title>Industry Standards</title>
				<para>StyleVision is a very flexible tool, which allows it to support different industry standard DTDs and schemas with ease. Here is an example of HTML and CALS tables in a DocBook document:</para>
				<para>
					<table width="70%" border="1">
						<caption>This is a sample HTML table</caption>
						<tbody>
							<tr>
								<td height="75" colspan="2">Sample</td>
								<td colspan="2" height="75" rowspan="2">data</td>
							</tr>
							<tr>
								<td>is spread </td>
								<td rowspan="2">over</td>
							</tr>
							<tr>
								<td/>
								<td>the </td>
								<td>whole table</td>
							</tr>
						</tbody>
					</table>
				</para>
				<para>
					<table>
						<title>This is a sample CALS table</title>
						<tgroup cols="3">
							<colspec colname="spycolgen1" colwidth="0.750000*"/>
							<colspec colname="spycolgen2" colwidth="0.750000*"/>
							<colspec colname="spycolgen3" colwidth="1.500000*"/>
							<tbody>
								<row>
									<entry namest="spycolgen1" nameend="spycolgen2">Sample</entry>
									<entry colname="spycolgen3">data</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>is spread</entry>
									<entry morerows="1" colname="spycolgen2">over</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry/>
									<entry>the whole table</entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
				</para>
			</sect1>
			<sect1>
				<title>Views</title>
				<para>The StyleVision user interface includes six synchronized tabs that allow you to save and view the stylesheets and output generated from your design directly in the design window. Each tab allows you to toggle between viewing the stylesheet and its associated output. Tabs include:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis role="bold">Design tab </emphasis>for viewing your design. Clicking the tab toggles to the JavaScript editor, where you define JavaScript functions for your design. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis role="bold">Authentic tab </emphasis>for viewing the Authentic electronic form generated by your design.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis role="bold">Preview HTML tab </emphasis>for viewing HTML output. Clicking the tab toggles to the standards-conformant XSLT 1.0/2.0 stylesheet that generates HTML output. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis role="bold">Preview RTF tab </emphasis>for viewing RTF output. Clicking the tab toggles to the standards-conformant XSLT 1.0/2.0 stylesheet that generates RTF output. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis role="bold">Preview PDF tab </emphasis>for viewing HTML output. Clicking the tab toggles to the standards-conformant XSLT 1.0/2.0 stylesheet that generates HTML output. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis role="bold">Preview Word 2007 tab </emphasis>for viewing OOXML output. Clicking the tab toggles to the standards-conformant XSLT 1.0/2.0 stylesheet that generates Microsoft® Word 2007+ output.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</sect1>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>Electronic Forms Design</title>
			<sect1>
				<title>Altova StyleVision® 2010 is a flexible and powerful application for designing electronic forms based on XML and/or database content.</title>
				<para>Electronic forms provide large and small businesses with a highly efficient alternative to paper-based systems, promoting the automation of business processes and streamlining data collection.</para>
				<para>StyleVision offers advanced functionality for creating electronic forms based on the same design paradigm used in many desktop publishing applications. An alternative approach to traditional StyleVision stylesheet design, this lets you design your electronic form first using absolute positioning, fixed lines, etc., and concentrate on adding dynamic and/or user-defined content after. You can even upload a blueprint image to serve as a guide in the design process.</para>
				<para>Once your design is complete, you can easily distribute the electronic forms to any number of users for manual completion in Altova Authentic® 2010. For more information on how StyleVision works with Authentic, see the Report Builder page.</para>
			</sect1>
			<sect1>
				<title>Electronic Forms Layout</title>
				<para>To create an electronic form in StyleVision, you begin with a new (empty) form-based document. This lets you format your document based on absolute coordinates and provides you with direct control over the precise layout of your electronic form. StyleVision will prompt you to upload an optional blueprint image, which can be useful if you are basing your form on an existing design.

electronic forms design.</para>
				<para>
					<inlinegraphic fileref="http://www.altova.com/images/shots/layout_container.gif"/>
				</para>
			</sect1>
		</chapter>
	</part>
</book>
