<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Sample XML file generated by XMLSpy v2008 (http://www.altova.com)-->
<book author="Altova" ISBN="(none)" publisher="Altova" volumes="One" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="Book with RichEdit.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<overview>
		<Style css="color: teal; text-align: left">
			<p>In this document we give an overview of StyleVision and Authentic products.</p>
		</Style>
		<Style css="color: teal; text-align: left">
			<p>First, StyleVision features like design, standard conformance or database reporting are highlited. Then one can learn more about Authentic specifics like content editing and industry-standards support.</p>
		</Style>
	</overview>
	<chapter>
		<heading heading-style="color: #803b00; font-family: Aharoni; font-size: 18pt; font-weight: bold; text-align: center">StyleVision Overview</heading>
		<subchapter>
			<heading heading-style="color: #2400c0; font-family: Arial; font-size: 14pt">Create Eye-Catching Output</heading>
			<p>Altova StyleVision 2008 features a unique graphical design interface for creating stylesheets to transform <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> and database data into multiple output formats. Because StyleVision produces standards-conformant <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSLT 1.0</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSLT 2.0</Style>, and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSL:FO</Style> stylesheets, plus <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Word/RTF</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">PDF</Style>, and Authentic form output <Style css="font-style: italic">simultaneously</Style>, based on one design, developers and designers no longer need to spend countless hours hand-coding and testing intricate stylesheets to implement single source publishing and database reporting solutions.</p>
		</subchapter>
		<subchapter>
			<heading heading-style="color: #2400c0; font-family: Arial; font-size: 14pt">Visual Stylesheet Design</heading>
			<p>Writing even the simplest transformation stylesheets manually is a difficult, time-consuming process. It requires an understanding of <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSL</Style> elements, the <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XPath</Style> language, and complicated rules-based document processing models. StyleVision 2008 abstracts away the tricky underlying syntax, allowing you to compose stylesheets using a visual design interface, which is easier to learn, takes considerably less time, reduces the occurrence of errors, and lets you focus on the creativity of your design. The designs you create in StyleVision can be based on any <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">DTD</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML Schema</Style>, or relational database, and multiple sources are supported. For instance, you can create one design that includes data from both <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> and database sources.</p>
			<p>The unified design approach promoted by StyleVision allows you to implement <Style css="text-decoration: underline">true single source publishing</Style>, since one easy-to-create design simultaneously produces <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Word/RTF</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">PDF</Style>, and electronic form output. When your source data changes, the <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Word/RTF</Style>, and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">PDF</Style> output can be updated simultaneously with the click of a button.</p>
		</subchapter>
		<subchapter>
			<heading heading-style="color: #2400c0; font-family: Arial; font-size: 14pt">Advanced Styles and Functions</heading>
			<p>Applying eye-catching styles and advanced functionality to your designs is easy with StyleVision's drag-and-drop design process and intelligent entry-helpers. To create a design, you simply drag elements from your data source(s) onto the design pane, and StyleVision 2008 prompts you with options for rendering the content. You can insert static content, such as headers, images, etc., directly into your design, then insert elements from <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> and database sources that will be rendered dynamically based on the source data.You can even re-use portions of existing design files when creating new designs. To help you apply layout and style information to the content in your design, StyleVision includes advanced entry-helper windows and dialog boxes for viewing and editing source elements and styles. Design styles can be applied using drag-and-drop functionality or by editing properties directly in the entry-helpers.</p>
			<p>For <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style> Web page design, StyleVision supports all the elements found on today's advanced Web pages, including hyperlinks, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">CSS</Style> (cascading stylesheets), JavaScript functions, and more. It even includes a JavaScript editor for defining functions that add dynamic, event-based functionality to your <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style> pages.</p>
			<p>StyleVision allows you to apply <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">CSS</Style> styles on a local or global basis using drop-down menus and dialog boxes, and you can also import an external <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">CSS</Style> stylesheet to apply previously created rules to your StyleVision design. <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">CSS</Style> styles are applied to your <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style> output, and most translate to <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Word/RTF</Style> and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">PDF</Style> output as well.</p>
			<p>The table of contents capability, complete with its TOC wizard and context-sensitive right click menu, makes StyleVision even more attractive for <Style css="font-style: italic">single source, multi-channel publishing</Style>. This is especially true for publishing large documents, which may have source content in <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> or databases and require tables of contents when output to <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Word</Style>, and/or <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">PDF</Style>.</p>
			<p>In addition to defining advanced style and layout conditions, StyleVision allows you to design stylesheets and Authentic forms that support advanced functions such as complex table handling, rich input formatting, business logic validation, date control, and more. All these features, combined with the ease of visual, drag-and-drop design, make StyleVision an invaluable tool for Web developers and others who need to publish <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> and database content in online and print media.</p>
		</subchapter>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<heading heading-style="color: #803b00; font-family: Aharoni; font-size: 18pt; font-weight: bold; text-align: center">Further Highlights</heading>
		<subchapter>
			<heading heading-style="color: #2400c0; font-family: Arial; font-size: 14pt">Database Report Generation</heading>
			<p>Because StyleVision 2008 allows you to base your design on a relational database (in addition to a <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">DTD</Style> or <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML Schema</Style>), it's easy to design database reports with output to <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Word/RTF</Style>, and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">PDF</Style>. A <Style css="text-decoration: underline">new Database Query window</Style> allows you to easily connect to and query databases from within the application. What's more, StyleVision 2008 works directly with <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> data stored inside <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">IBM DB2 9</Style> databases. Users simply associate database <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> fields with <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML Schemas</Style>, then drag elements onto the design pane for rendering and publishing.</p>
		</subchapter>
		<subchapter>
			<heading heading-style="color: #2400c0; font-family: Arial; font-size: 14pt">Standards-conformant Stylesheet Creation</heading>
			<p>Based on your visual design, StyleVision 2008 auto-generates multiple transformation stylesheets to convert your <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> and database data to <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Word/RTF</Style>, and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">PDF</Style>. StyleVision supports <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSLT 1.0</Style> and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSL:FO</Style>, as well as the powerful <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSLT 2.0</Style> stylesheet specification. <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSLT 2.0</Style> support is <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML Schema</Style>-aware, providing additional mechanisms for error isolation and enhanced code performance. Based on your choice of <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSLT 1.0</Style> or <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">2.0</Style>, StyleVision auto-generates the <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSLT</Style> code and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XPath 1.0</Style> or <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">2.0</Style> selectors required to build your stylesheets. This automated design approach speeds stylesheet creation and all but negates the occurrence of errors.</p>
			<p>At any time during the design process, you can view and save the <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSLT</Style> and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSL:FO</Style> stylesheets that are built behind the scenes based on your design. Since they are standards-based, you can use these stylesheets in other applications as needed.</p>
		</subchapter>
		<subchapter>
			<heading heading-style="color: #2400c0; font-family: Arial; font-size: 14pt">HTML to XML Conversion</heading>
			<p>To leverage existing Web content, StyleVision 2008 includes a handy <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style> importer for converting <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style> to <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style>. Using simple drag-and-drop functionality, you can quickly convert an <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style> page to an <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML Schema</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSLT 1.0</Style> or <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">2.0</Style> stylesheet, and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> instance document. This feature adds extensibility to your current <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style> content, which can now be used in <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style>-based applications and output in <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Word/RTF</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">PDF</Style>, and Altova Authentic form formats.</p>
		</subchapter>
		<subchapter>
			<heading heading-style="color: #2400c0; font-family: Arial; font-size: 14pt">Authentic Form Creation</heading>
			<p>In addition to rendering attractive <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Word/RTF</Style>, and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">PDF</Style> output, each design you create in StyleVision 2008 can also produce an Authentic form for use with Altova Authentic 2008. Authentic is a free <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> and database content editor that allows non-technical business users to access and edit content in <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> documents and relational databases without being exposed to the underlying technology. They simply fill in electronic forms created in StyleVision, and the source <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> documents or databases are automatically accessed and updated behind the scenes.</p>
			<p>Because your design also simultaneously produces <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSLT</Style> and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XSL:FO</Style> stylesheets along with the Authentic form, you can output the data entered through the form directly to <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">HTML</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Word/RTF</Style>, and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">PDF</Style> without having to design additional stylesheets. More about Authentic 2008 is included on the following page.</p>
		</subchapter>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<heading heading-style="color: #803b00; font-family: Aharoni; font-size: 18pt; font-weight: bold; text-align: center">Authentic</heading>
		<subchapter>
			<heading heading-style="color: #2400c0; font-family: Arial; font-size: 14pt">Unlock Corporate Knowledge</heading>
			<p>Altova Authentic 2008 offers an innovative approach to <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> and database content editing that completely shields the end user from the underlying technology. Authentic presents non-technical business users with electronic forms that allow them to view and enter valid <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> or database data using intuitive, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">WYSIWYG</Style> forms. These electronic Authentic forms are created by designers using Altova StyleVision 2008.</p>
			<p>Authentic forms can be based on any <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">DTD</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML Schema</Style>, or relational database. And, since Authentic is offered under a free license, you can distribute the Authentic forms interface to as many end users as required free of charge.</p>
		</subchapter>
		<subchapter>
			<heading heading-style="color: #2400c0; font-family: Arial; font-size: 14pt">XML and Database Content Editing</heading>
			<p>Authentic 2008 is available as a FREE download in Desktop and Browser Editions. The Desktop Edition is an independently managed client application, while the Browser Edition provides similar viewing and editing capabilities in a lightweight plug-in component that runs inside the Internet Explorer browser.</p>
		</subchapter>
		<subchapter>
			<heading heading-style="color: #2400c0; font-family: Arial; font-size: 14pt">Industry Template Support</heading>
			<p>In addition to supporting Authentic forms created with StyleVision 2008, Authentic 2008 includes built-in templates for saving data according to industry <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XML</Style> standards such as <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">DITA</Style> (Darwin Information Typing Architecture), <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">DocBook</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">NITF</Style> (News Industry Text Format), <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">NewsML</Style> (News Markup Language), and many others. Using the Authentic templates, non-technical users can quickly edit and save data that is valid according to these widely-used schemas.</p>
			<p>Authentic 2008 is available in free Desktop and Browser Editions in both English and German language versions. It is supported on <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Windows 2000</Style>, <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">XP</Style>, and <Style css="font-family: Cordia New">Vista</Style>. You may download a free copy of Authentic at www.altova.com/download.</p>
		</subchapter>
	</chapter>
</book>
